Guide to the Clarence Leslie Hix Papers 1903-1980
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Clarence Leslie Hix Papers
1903-1980
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 508
Hix, Clarence Leslie
4 containers. 3 linear feet of shelf space. 1867 items.
Finance records, minutes, insurance and bond papers, hand books and photographs that deal with his work at Washington State University. Also, personal bills, real estate transactions, stocks, insurance papers, and personal papers of some family members which includes much memorabilia.
Clarence Leslie Hix was born in Filmore, Montana, on October 31, 1886. His family later moved to Spokane, Washington, where Clarence attended the old Spokane High School. After graduating high school, he came to Pullman as a freshman at Washington State College in 1905. Although he lived in a dormitory, he belonged to a local fraternity which became Sigma Phi Epsilon in 1912. He graduated in 1909 with a B.S. in civil engineering and with high honors. He also had a degree in mathematics. Hix taught mathematics at Pullman High School from 1909 until 1911. He then became a math instructor at Washington State College, from 1911 until 1919. He married Miss Hettie Cave in 1916. She was also a Washington State College graduate. She received a degree in Home Economics in 1915. Hix had a long career at Washington State College. He became Chief Accountant in 1919, and later worked in the Comptroller's office during World War II. After the war he was the retirement and insurance officer and in 1949 was appointed the budget officer, a position he held until his retirement in 1957.
Hix was also involved in campus organizations. He was elected treasurer of the Washington State University Alumni Association in 1920, and retained that position for 63 years. The alumni lounge was dedicated in his name in 1978. He was also the treasurer for Sigma Phi Epsilon for over half a century, and for this he received their highest honor, the Golden Heart. Hix served on numerous committees, boards, councils, and commissions on campus and in the Pullman community. He was a member of the Pullman Foundation and was the Blue Lion's Club secretary for many years. He died on November 17, 1983 at the age of 97.
The papers of Clarence Leslie Hix span the years 1930 through 1978.
The papers of Clarence Leslie Hix are arranged in two series. The first series consists of his work in Sigma Phi Epsilon, the Blue Lion's Club, Washington State University, and other councils and committees he had worked on. Included in this first series are nine Washington State University Farm Fact books, consisting of the revenues and expenditures of the University farm, spanning the years 1936 - 1957. These are placed in the oversized box. Oversize folder #74 contains fraternity and campus blueprints also belonging to the first series. This series contains finance records, minutes, insurance and bonds papers, handbooks and photographs, and all deal with his life work during his career at Washington State University. This series spans the years 1925 - 1973. The folders are ordered by the amount of material of each category, the largest starting off the series.
The second series is of a personal nature, and deals with Hix's personal bills, real estate transactions, stocks, and insurance papers. This series also contains some personal papers of his wife Hettie Hix, his son Richard Hix, and his in-laws, Marie and Glenn Glover. Marie was the sister of Hettie Hix. This series is the bulk of the collection, and included in it are photographs, newspapers clippings, handbooks, gamebooks, and old school papers. There is also a great deal of memorabilia, such as World War I and World War II maps and newspapers, and in the oversized box, there is a W.S.U. Evergreen from 1909, Richard Hix's R.O.T.C. buttons from WSU, ca. 1940, and of special interest, a satirical John F. Kennedy Coloring Book ca. 1960. This series spans the years 1903 - 1980, and the folders are ordered by importance; Clarence Hix's personal papers are first, followed by Hettie, Richard, family items, and then Marie and Glenn Glover. The oversized folder is placed in a drawer in the mapcase of the Archives.
This collection is open for research use.
The papers of Clarence L. Hix were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by Keith Lincoln of the Alumni Office, and were received on July 25, 1980 (MS80-25).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Hix, Clarence Leslie, 1886-1983 --Archives; Lincoln, Keith. waps
Washington State University--Miscellanea; Washington State University--Faculty -- Archives
Colleges and Universities; Scrapbooks; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Clarence Hix Work Papers
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon Fraternity; finance, records, 1954-1969; 33 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Board: Sigma Phi Epsilon Fraternity; records, 1958-1959; 83 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Board: Sigma Phi Epsilon Fraternity; records, 1958-1959; 29 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon Fraternity; handbooks, photographs, miscellaneous, 1925-1971; 16 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blue Lion's Club; New Sigma Phi Epsilon house, 1916-1925; 56 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blue Lion's Club; mortgage bonds, 1925-1941; 25 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blue Lion's Club; mortgage bonds, 1926-1949; 24 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blue Lion's Club; insurance papers, bankbook, 1925-1954; 19 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Blue Lion's Club and Washington Alpha papers, 1967-1973; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wilson Compton Student Union Building Rules, 1952; 118 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Contract Manual - Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1945; 94 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Contract Manual - Office of Scientific Research and Developement, 1945; 123 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Washington State University; handbooks, pamphlets, 1915-1946; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Washington State University; handbooks, pamphlets, 1946-1968; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Washington State University; newspaper articles, photographs, miscellaneous, 1938-1959; 22 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pullman Foundation Committee Papers, 1949-1973; 114 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Whitman County Council on Aging Papers, 1977; 49 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Friends of the Library; pamphlets, 1945-1967; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Milwaukee - Puget Sound Pioneer's Club; meeting notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - City of Pullman; collected papers about Pullman, 1937-1970; 18 items. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Papers, letters during Hix's position of Budget officer at Washington State University, 1928-1957; 64 items. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series 2: Clarence Hix and Family Personal Papers
  - Clarence Hix; bills, receipts, statements, 1903-1980; 18 items. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clarence Hix; real estate transactions, 1915-1971; 27 items. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clarence Hix; Sterling Company Stocks and Bonds, 1919-1923; 7 items. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Clarence Hix; social security, insurance, medical, 1954-1971; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Clarence Hix; list of owned items, assests, 1920-1950; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clarence Hix; awards, citations, congratulations, 1918-1957; 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Clarence Hix; school notebook, 1905; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clarence Hix; correspondence, 1933-1957; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Clarence Hix; personal miscellaneous, 1909-1968; 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hettie Hix; scrapbook, 1920-1940; 76 items. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hettie Hix; scrapbook, 1920-1940; 39 items. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hettie Hix; scrapbook, 1920-1940; 63 items. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Hettie Hix; calendar cutouts, 1950-1955; 55 items. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - C. Richard Hix; personal miscellaneous, 1933-1945; 26 items. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Clarence and Hettie Hix; miscellaneous collections, 1915-1960; 93 items. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Photographs, 1900-1976; 38 items. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Postcards from family and friends, 1909-1950; 34 items. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Postcards from family and friends, 1950-1979; 34 items. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Postcard advertisements, 1953-1958; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Traveling pamphlets, maps, 1920-1955; 22 items. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Newspapers clippings of Clarence Hix, 1956-1978; 26 items. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Family newspaper clippings, 1935-1963; 32 items. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1935-1965; 33 items. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Saved newspapers, 1934-1958; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - World War I and II memorabilia, 1934-1946; 17 items. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Math, games, and puzzle books, 1920-1957; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous books, 1929-1953; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous books, 1903-1937; 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Glenn and Marie Glover; old tax receipts and store notes, 1912-1945; 47 items. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Glenn and Marie Glover; real estate, stocks, and Kappa Alpha Theta notes, 1916-1930; 14 items. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Marie Glover; rcords, power of attorney, medicare, 1958-1972; 6 items. (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Marie Glover; old school items, family items, 1918-1948; 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Marie Glover; party arrangements, notes, 1927-1974; 63 items. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Marie Glover; baby announcements, notes, 1950-1958; 20 items. (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Oversized box: Items belonging to both series
  - Richard Hix; R.O.T.C. buttons from Washington State University, 1940; 34 items. (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Richard Hix; boy scout buttons, 1934; 37 items. (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Clarence Hix; travel kit, 1920; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Washington State Farm Records, 1936-1957; 9 items. (Box 4, Folder 59-67)
  - John F. Kennedy Coloring Book, 1960; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Clarence Hix; 2nd Lieutenant Document, 1907; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Clarence Hix; Golden Grad Reunion Memento, 1959; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Hettie Hix; Golen Grad Reunion Memento, 1965; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Camp Roberts Trainer Book, 1940; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Washington State University Evergreen, 1909; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Oversized Folder: Fraternity blueprints, campus blueprints, and Richard Hix army photo, 1944-1956; 20 items. (Box O.S., Folder 74)